A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Instruments FA240
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Instruments
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
New York University
Cornell University
Cornell University. Medical College
Rockefeller University
FA240
3 Cubic Feet 5 boxes. Extent volume is approximate.
5 boxes
Arrangement
Arranged primarily alphabetically.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 851
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Medical research; Medical education; Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biochemistry; Science -- Study and teaching; Medical sciences; Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Architecture; Women; Women’s history; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; New York University; Cornell University; Cornell University. Medical College; Rockefeller University
- Catalogs of instruments from papers of individual scientists
  - American Cyanamid and Chemical Corp. Instructions for operating filt-r-stil, undated (Box 1)
  - American Instrument Co., 1938 1947 1953 (Box 1)
  - American Platinum Works, undated (Box 1)
  - American Radiator Co., 1927 1928 1930 (Box 1)
  - Ansco Color Film, undated; 8 items (Box 1)
  - Baker Company 2 items on platinum ware, undated (Box 1)
  - Bausch & Lomb Optical Co., undated; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Becbro Laboratory Rheostats cat. 20, undated (Box 1)
  - Black Light Eastern Corp. Pen-ray "mercury pencil" lamp & items, undated (Box 1)
  - Bond Standard Stock Gears cat. 56, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Boston Gears, 1926 1926 1930 (Box 1)
  - Cambridge Instrument Company List no. 100, 167, 169 (Box 1)
  - Instructions for Compton Electrometer (Box 1)
  - Commercial Plastics and Supply Corp (Teflon), 1956 (Box 1)
  - Contoure (photocopier), undated (Box 1)
  - Coors Porcelain Co., 1939 (Box 1)
  - Corning Glass Works, 1938 1949 1952 1953 1954 1956 undated (Box 1)
  - Electric Storage Battery Co. 1st ed., 8th ed (Box 1)
  - Electronic symbols (Military standard), 1948 1952 (Box 1)
  - Eck & Krebs (Special list of laboratory glassware), undated (Box 1)
  - Fenwal Inc. (Thermoswitch controls), 1946 (Box 1)
  - General Electric Co. (Photo-electric cell), 1925 (Box 1)
  - General Radio Company (Box 1)
    - "Experimenter", 1941-1942 1944 September 1953 July
    - Bridges, Catalog K
    - Parts and components
    - Instructions for Megohm Bridge
    - Instructions for Strootac
    - Catalog, N, O, P
  - Variac transformers, undated; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Greibach meters (Box 2)
  - H & B Products, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Hanovia Quartz ware, Bulletin, 10 items (Box 2)
  - Hoke Incorporated (Regulators), 1947 (Box 2)
  - International Equipment Co. (Centrifuge), 1925 (Box 2)
  - Kimble Glass (Laboratory glassware), 1947 (Box 2)
  - Klett Electrophoresis Apparatus; a manual, 1948 (Box 2)
  - E. Machlett & Son 2 items mercury switches and equipment (Box 2)
  - Leeds and Northrup Co., 3 of 1927, 2 of 1928, 1930, 1939, 1940, 1945, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Optical Film Engineering Co., 1 item (Box 2)
  - Rubicon Company (Potentiometers, Electrometer, Galvanometer, circa 1950 (Box 2)
  - Sensitive Research Instrument Co., circa 1950 (Box 2)
  - Spencer Lens Co., 1930 (Box 2)
  - Terminal Radio Corp., 1952 (Box 2)
  - U.S. National Bureau of Standards (Weights) Circ. 547 sect. 1, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Variac-Powerstat transformers. Operating instructions, undated (Box 2)
  - Weston Electrical Instrument (Box 2)
    - Instruction book for #772 analyzer
    - Catalog B-36-C Instruments, undated
  - S.S. White Engineering Bulletin 38, 1938 Flexible shafts (Box 2)
  - Yellow Springs Instrument Co. Temperature controllers 2 items, undated (Box 2)
- Operating instructions for instruments from G.E. Perlmann papers
  Scope and Contents note
  Also includes some catalogs, (dated if known).
  - Air conditioners (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Airgard Mfg. Co., undated; 3 items
    - Fedders, undated; 3 items
    - Friedrich, undated
  - Amino Acid Analyzer (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beckman (Applications Data Sheet), undated
  - Balances (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brinkmann (Sartorius: Projecta balance; 2100, 2500 series; service), undated; 5 items
    - Ohaus (heavy duty solution balance), undated
    - Torsion, undated; 2 items
  - Baths (Water) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Arthur H. Thomas (9935- Tecam Tempunit), undated
    - Brinkmann Thermo-Cool, undated
    - Cenco Knife Type Heaters, undated
    - Electric Heat Control Apparatus (Elconap), undated
    - Fenwal Inc. (Thermoswitch units), undated
    - Haake Circulators (Series "ED"), 1964
    - Haake Circulators (Series "ND"), undated
    - Haake Thermostat Type "F" (Gebrüder Haake), undated
    - Haake Ultra-Thermostat (Gebrüder Haake), undated
    - Haake Constant Temperature Circulators (Models FJ and FE) (Polyscience Corp), undated
    - Lauda Table Model Kryomats (Low temperature circulators), undated
    - Techne Ltd. (Tecam Tempunit - Samson 2246), undated
    - Thomas, Arthur H. (See Arthur H. Thomas)
  - Calculators (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Friden (Singer) (1115 electronic calculator), undated; 5 items
    - Victor (Series 1800), undated; 2 items
  - Centrifuges (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Sorvall (RC2-B), undated
  - Conductivity Meter (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Radiometer (Type CDM2), undated; 4 items
      Includes Okholm reprint "Conductivity method for the control of a soap dryer"
  - Dicrographs (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cary Instruments (6001 Circular Dichroism Accessory for Cary Model 60 Spectropolarimeter), 1967
  - Electrodes (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Radiometer (Glass Electrode Type G2222 B or C), undated
  - Electrophoresis (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Heathkit (Model IP-17), 1970
    - Savant Instruments (Instructions for: Junction Box 1967, Tanks and Flat Plates [undated]; high voltage paper 1963), 4 items
  - Electrofocusing (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - LKB (8100 Ampholine), 1972
  - Evaporators (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Buchler (Model #PF-10DN), 1972
    - E. Machlett & Son, undated
  - Fraction Collectors (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Gilson Medical Electronics (GME Fractionators), 1964; 2 items
    - Metalglass Inc. (Compact Fraction Collectors), undated; 2 items
    - RU (Operating instructions and schematics for fraction collector control system), 1972-1973
    - Standard Instrument Corp. (Tally count model 7C-317), 1959
    - Technicon Chromatography Corp., 1955, undated; 3 items
  - Glass Blower (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Scientific Glass Rockefeller 573882) Pyrex 1958 (Diagram with specifications)
  - Head Phones (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Brush Development Co. ("A" and "B" headphones), 1947
  - Laboratory Maintenance Instructions (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Coleman Instruments (cuvettes), 1946
    - Corning Glass Works (Laboratory glass blowing, - pyrex), undated
    - Fasman (cell holder for Cary 60 - diagrams), undated; 3 items
    - Matheson Co. (Safe handling of compressed gases in laboratory and plant), 1963; 3 items
    - RU (Maintenance of laboratories 1963-1964; Safe handling and use of compressed gases 1971), 1963-1964 1971; 3 items
  - Mineralight (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ultra-Violet Products (Ultra-violet lampes), undated; 3 items
  - Mixers (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lab-Line Instruments (Magnestir #1250 - 1965; Super-Mixer #1290 - 1964), 1964-1965; 2 items
    - Radiometer (Stirring motor assembly), undated
    - Scientific Industries (Vortex-genie test tube mixer and Vortex-shaker), undated; 2 items
    - Tri R Instruments (Magnetic stirrer), undated
  - Ovens (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Blue M Electric Co. (Models OV-8 and OV-12 Series - 1953; Model OM-10 - 1961), 1953-1961; 2 items
    - pH meter drawings, undated
  - Pipette Dryer (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Virtis Co. (Filtered air pipette dryer, 15-60), undated
  - Pipetting Machines (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Brewer Automatic Pipetting Machine, 1950
    - Brinkman Instruments Inc. (Eppendorf microliter pipet), undated
    - National Instrument Co. (Filamatic portable, aseptic filling machine), undated
  - Pressure Regulators (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Moore Products Co., 1950
  - Pumps (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Buchler Instruments, 1972
    - Precision Scientific Co., undated
    - Welch Scientific Co., 1964
  - Radioactive file (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - New England Nuclear Corp. (Photocopy "Atomlight" - keyword index of Atomlight articles and authors Issues 1-49), undated
    - RU (Regulations for the use of radioactive isotopes), 1966 January
    - RU Committee on Radioisotopes communication (from R.M. Archibald, Chairman), 1966 January 15
    - RU Radio-Isotope Committee memorandum regarding purchase of radioisotopes, 1968 January 23
    - NYC Notice to employees on Standards for protection against radiation, undated
    - RU instructions for procedures to be followed in case of emergency, undated
  - Refrigerator (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - General Electric, undated
    - Sears (Coldspot Freezer) Owner's guide: Repair parts list for, undated; 2 items
    - United Refrigerator Co., undated
  - Spectrophotometers (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - P.H. Coleman, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gilford Instrument, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Model 244 Automatic Cuvette Positioner, 1968
      - Model 240 Spectrophotometer, 1969
      - Model 2220 Adapter, 1970
      - Model 6040 Recorder, 1971
    - Carl Zeiss, 7 items (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Spectrophotometer PMQ11, undated; 2 items
      - Chromatogram Attachment CA2 for PMQ11, undated
      - Reflective Attachment RA3 for PMQ11, undated
      - Fluorescence Attachment ZFM4 for PMQ11, undated
      - Sphere Attachment for for PMQ11, undated
      - Temporary Cell Holder for PMQ11, undated
  - Spectropolarimeter (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Reprint Cary, H. et al "A recording spectropolarimeter", 1964 March
    - Cary Instruments, 1963
    - Osram (Xenon lamps XBO)
    - RI Instrument Shop (Column - drawing), 1964
  - Temperature Controllers (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fenwal Inc. (Thermoswitch units), undated
    - Polyscience Corp. (Constant temperature circulator model EDe "Unitherm"), 1967
    - Precision Scientific Co. (Precision electronic relay control box), 1955
  - Twin Layer Chromatography (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brinkman Instruments (Operating manual 103-C), undated
    - Nester/Faust Mfg. Corp. (TLC Handbook - Quantitative aspects of thin layer chromatography), undated
  - Transferator (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gilson Medical Electronics (GME automatic transferator), undated; 2 items
  - Transformers (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Drawings of circuits, undated; 4 items
  - Ultraviolet Analyzers (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Instrumentation Specialties Co. Isco Model UA2, undated; 2 items
    - Isco Model UA (Recording Ultraviolet analyzer), undated
  - Universal Timer (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gralab (Models 172 and 173), undated
  - Voltmeters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Precision Apparatus Co. (Model 110), undated
    - Triplett (Model 630-A type 2 Volt-Ohm - milliammeter), undated
- The Merck Index, 1940 Pharmacopeia of the U.S., 14th Revision, 1950 (Box 5)
- Modern Laboratory Appliances (Eimer and Amend, Fisher Scientific Company, 1946) (Box 5)
- Modern Laboratory Appliances (Fisher Scientific Company, 1934) (Box 5)
- General Catalog of Laboratory Apparatus and Scientific Instruments (Central Scientific Company, 1936) (Box 5)
- File Inventory, Purchasing Department, 1983 (Box 5)
- "Enterprise" Electrical Coffee Mills and Meat & Food Choppers, 1919 (Box 5)
- The Medical Letter: Handbook of Adverse Drug Interactions, 1987 (Box 5)